Guide to the Donald Currier Papers
Yale University Music Library
Donald Currier Papers
1948-2009
MSS 109
Yale University Music Library
3
(7 containers)
Currier, Donald
Arrangement
Materials in this collection have been kept in their original order - files by date and files by subject.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Currier (1919-2010) was was a professor of piano at the Yale School of Music. He attended the New England Conservatory as an undergraduate, and served in the U.S. Army during World War II. Currier joined the faculty at Yale in 1951, and remained there until his retirement in 1989. He was an active performer and teacher of the piano. He often collaborated with fellow faculty and students, including Helen Boatwright, Keith Wilson, and Blake Stern. Currier also served as a Resident Fellow at Branford College and as Associate Dean of the School of Music.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been kept in their original order: files organized by date, and files organized by subject.
Scope and Contents
The materials in the collection relate to Currier's career as a pianist and faculty member at the Yale School of Music. Included are letters, programs, reviews, lecture notes, posters, and a few photographs. Currier included a number of sound recordings with his Papers. These include solo performances by Currier, and collaborations with other Yale School of Music faculty members. To access these recordings, please contact the Historical Sound Recordings department.
Related Materials
Researchers may also wish to consult the Yale School of Music Papers (MSS 3), also held by the Irving S. Gilmore Music Library.
Related Materials
Researchers may also wish to consult the Interview with Donald Currier, held by the Oral History of American Music (call number: OHI30/9a).
Currier, Donald; Yale School of Music
- Files by date, 1948-2009
  Scope and Contents
  Files by date contain programs from Currier's own performances, as well as performances he attended. Related reviews, correspondence, and a few photos are also included.
  - Box 1, 1948-1965
  - Box 2, 1966-1976
  - Box 3, 1977-1988
  - Box 4, 1989-2009
- Files by subject
  - Mozart (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lecture CSMTA 10/18/81 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Lecture, 06/83 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Recital, Branford College 1/15/81 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tonality -- Bach & Beethoven (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Schumann (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Contemporary Music (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mahler Symphonies & Conductor, Character (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Beethoven & Brahms (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Schumann Op. 13 Fantasie (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Haydn (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Beethoven Middle Sonatas (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Schubert B-flat Sonata (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Branford Seminar (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Lecture notes [spiral bound] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Annotated bibliography [note cards] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - New Haven Symphony, 4/15/58 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - California Concert & 1956 Concert Engagements (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - London Recital (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Recital Hall 2/24/61 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Town Hall Recital10/21/56 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Netherlands Concert 4/17/50 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - European Concerts 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Op. 110 Beethoven (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "European purchases" receipts and Trip Diary (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Oversize concert posters (Box 7)
  Posters from concerts and recitals including "Collegium Orchestra, Donald Currier, Gustav Meier" at Sprague Memorial Hall; "Piano Concert met Donald Currier" at Volksuniversiteit - entschede; "First Appearance in England of the American Pianist Donald Currier" in London; Donald Currier at Concertgebouw on 27 April 1950; and "Premier Recital du Pianiste Americain Donald Currier" at Salle Chopin-Pleyel, Paris on 17 April 1950.
  There are five posters, all of which appear to be from c. 1950-1975.